## STAVROS TSOGKAS

MaRS Discovery District 101 College St., Toronto, Ontario, Canada http://www.cs.toronto.edu/~tsogkas email: tsogkas@cs.toronto.edu

## Research Interests

My research interests are in the broad areas of computer vision and machine learning, with a focus on deep learning. I am particularly interested in the use of mid-level representations to bridge the gap between bottom-up and top-down processing and solve problems such as object detection, segmentation and grouping. I have devoted a large part of my research on recovering such representations, medial axes and object parts in particular, in natural and medical images.

#### Education

### CentraleSupélec

Jan. 2016

Ph.D. in Mathematics and Computer Science

Thesis: Mid-level Representations for Modeling Objects

Advisor: Iasonas Kokkinos

#### National Technical University of Athens

Sep. 2011

Diploma in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Thesis: Learning-Based Symmetry Detection in Natural Images

Advisors: Petros Maragos, Iasonas Kokkinos

# Peer-reviewed Conference Publications

- Geometric Disentanglement for Generative Latent Shape Models, ICCV 2019
   T. Aumentado-Armstrong, S. Tsogkas, A. Jepson, S. Dickinson
- DeepFlux for Skeletons in the Wild, CVPR 2019
   Y. Wang, Y. Xu, S. Tsogkas, X. Bei, S. Dickinson, K. Siddiqi
- AMAT: Medial Axis Transform for Natural Images, ICCV 2017
   S. Tsogkas, S. Dickinson
- Prior-based Coregistration and Cosegmentation, MICCAI 2016
   M. Shakeri\*, E. Ferrante\*, S. Tsogkas, S. Lippe, S. Kadoury, I. Kokkinos, N. Paragios (\* denotes equal contribution)
- Subcortical Brain Structure Segmentation Using FCNNs, ISBI 2016 (oral)
   S. Tsogkas\*, M. Shakeri\*, E. Ferrante, S. Lippe, S. Kadoury, N. Paragios, I. Kokkinos (\* denotes equal contribution)
- Accurate Human-Limb Segmentation in RGB-D images for Intelligent Mobility Assistance Robots

ICCV 2015 3<sup>rd</sup> Workshop on Assistive Computer Vision and Robotics S. Chandra, S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos

- Deformable Part Models with CNN Features,
   ECCV 2014 Parts and Attributes workshop
   P.-A. Savalle, S. Tsogkas, G. Papandreou and I. Kokkinos
- Superpixel-grounded Deformable Part Models, CVPR 2014
   E. Trulls, S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos, A. Sanfeliu, F.Moreno
- Understanding Objects in Detail with Fine-grained Attributes, CVPR 2014
   A. Vedaldi, S. Mahendran, S. Tsogkas, S. Maji, B. Girshick, J. Kannala, E. Rahtu, I. Kokkinos, M. B. Blaschko, D. Weiss, B. Taskar, K. Simonyan, N. Saphra, S. Mohamed

Learning-Based Symmetry Detection in Natural Images, ECCV 2012
 S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos

#### Reports

- ICCV 2017 Challenge: Detecting Symmetry in the Wild (editorial),

  Detecting symmetry in the wild workshop, ICCV 2017

  Chris Funk\*, Seungkyu Lee\*, Martin R. Oswald\*, Stavros Tsogkas\*, Wei
  Shen, Andrea Cohen, Sven Dickinson, Yanxi Liu (\* denotes equal contribution)
- - S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos, G. Papandreou, A. Vedaldi

## Research Experience

## Samsung AI Center Toronto

Sep. 2018 - present

Research Scientist

## Vector Institute for Artificial Intelligence

Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Affiliate postdoctoral fellow

## University of Toronto

Oct. 2016 - present

Postdoctoral fellow, Computer Science Department

Supervisor: Sven Dickinson

## CentraleSupélec

Jan. 2016 - Aug. 2016

Research engineer, CVN lab Supervisor: Nikos Paragios

Convolutional neural networks for semantic segmentation of organs in computed tomography scans.

### Oxford University (Visual Geometry Group)

Aug.-Nov. 2014

Research intern

Supervisor: Andrea Vedaldi.

Combined convolutional neural networks and restricted boltzmann machines for semantic segmentation of object parts.

# Teaching Experience

### Teaching assistant (CentraleSupélec)

2011-2015

- Signal Processing (undegrad course).
- Computer Vision (undegrad course).
- Machine Learning for Computer Vision (MVA master course)

#### Invited lecturer (CentraleSupélec/ESSEC)

2016

MSc in Data Science and Business Analytics Seminar on deep learning theory and tools.

## Professional Activities

Reviewer, IEEE TPAMI, IJCV, CVIU, IMAVIS, IEEE ICCV, IEEE CVPR, ECCV, ICVGIP, BMVC, Morgan & Claypool Synthesis lectures on Computer Vision

Co-organizer of the "Detecting Symmetry in the Wild" workshop,

in conjunction with ICCV 2017, Venice, Italy.

Treasurer, IEEE NTUA Student Branch2010-2011Chairman, IEEE NTUA Student Branch2011-2012Student member IEEE2012-2015

Programming Skills

MATLAB, Python, Lua, C++, Latex, Caffe, MatConvNet, Torch.

Outstanding reviewer award (ECCV 2016) Distinctions

 ${\bf Citizenship}$  ${\rm Greek}$ 

English (fluent), French (proficient), Greek (native). Languages